Sai Gautam Kolluru

Software Engineer

Sai Gautam Kolluru

206, Sri Lasya PG, Panchayat Office Road, Doddathogur, Electronic City, Bangalore, Karnataka - 560100

+91.939.534.5371 https://gauthamsk.me gautham.kolluru@gmail.com

Skills

I'm interested/excited/enjoy working with **Python** and **Data** and carry around **8+ Years** of experience in Automation, Scraping, Numpy, Pandas, Machine Learning and more from the Python family and MSSQL, MYSQL, Sqlite3 from the Databases. I'm excited to work in logical/analytical problem solving environments. I have huge penchant for Mathematics, Statistics, design and analysis of Algorithms and Physics. I can work efficiently on the below mentioned technologies and tools.

Machine Learning: Scikit Learn, RASA(NLP)

Data Processing / Analysis / Visualisation: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn

Programming: Python, Java, JavaScript, ColdFusion

Shell Scripting: PowerShell

Database: SQL Server, MYSQL, Sqlite3, MongoDB

Web Development and Scraping Frameworks: Scrapy, Django

Packages: Numpy, Web Scraping (BeautifulSoup, GoogleScraper,

newspaper3k, lxml etc...), Pandas

Database Reporting Tools: SQL Server Reporting Service, Tableau

Web UI: CSS, Bootstrap

Mark-up: HTML, CFML, XML, TOML, YAML

Markdown: Python, Pandoc

IDE & Text-Editor: PyCharm, VS Code, Anaconda (Jupyter), Google Colaboratory, VIM, Adobe Dreamweaver, Eclipse, Sublime Text, Atom,

Brackets, Notepad++

Version Control: GIT & GitHub, Subversion Networks (SVN)

Experience

Infosys / Consultant

July 2019 - PRESENT, Bangalore

Develop Chatbots using Open Source Natural Language Processing (NLP) framework RASA based on Python using both RASA NLU and RASA CORE for client Cisco.

Talent Sprint/ Consultant - Delivery

December 2018 - June 2019, Hyderabad

Analysing and visualising data and providing useful and game changing insights to improve the overall performance of the organisation.

Train corporates' new recruitees on Machine Learning

Global Data/ Software Engineer

August 2018 - December 2018, Hyderabad

Developed multiple automation scripts in python to pull xml.gz files from ftp and HTML files, parse the contents and save the contents in the DB without having repetitions and scheduled their execution using PowerShell.

Developed automation scripts in python to transfer data from one DB to another DB with different structures.

Invincible Software Solutions India Pvt. Ltd / Software Developer

December 2016 - July 2018, Visakhapatnam

Developed about 12 web applications using Coldfusion and Microsoft's SQL Server with bootstrap 3 for the responsive UI.

Developed SSRS & Tableau reports with descriptive analysis for 3 projects.

Trained the in-house team on Python

Coding Sastra / Python Consultant

January 2017 - Present, Visakhapatnam/Hyderabad

Introduced the Python course at the institute and curated the contents. Conducted workshops on Python on behalf of the institute.

Pythonworkshops.com / Python Trainer

January 2018 - Present, Visakhapatnam/Hyderabad

Conducted a 2-day workshop in association with **Andhra Pradesh Startup Society** (as part of a Startup Initiative) on 'Introduction to Programming with Python

Chegg.com / Python Trainer

November 2015 - November 2016, Visakhapatnam/Hyderabad

Trained students on Chegg's dedicated portal on Python and Core Java technologies.

Trifoil LLC / Project Engineer

February 2013 - October 2015, Muscat

Developed Database system for the Speed Radar System for the Royal Oman Police (client) and developed python scripts for Descriptive Data Analysis of the data generated.

Major project and client being the installation of Speed Radar Systems for the Royal Oman Police apart from which 14 other projects of system integration involving IPTV systems and Structured Cabling were handled.

Mott MacDonald / Automation Engineer

September 2009 - April 2012, Abu Dhabi

Consulting engineer for automating the Waste Water Treatment Plant at Yas Island, Vacuum Sewer System at Al Gurm Resort and Pumping Station at Emirati Housing Society - Phase 1.

Helped the organisation internally in automatically arranging the department's files and folder by developing automation scripts in python and using *Shell Utilities* and *OS* modules.

Education

Andhra University / Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science & Engineering

June 2005 - May 2009, Visakhapatnam, Andhra Pradesh

• -			re	_	L _
	_	_	r	С.	rc

Functional Programming

Design, development and implementation of algorithms

Researching on Machine Learning, Deep Learning involving Neural Networks

Online

https://github.com/gauthamkolluru/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/gautamkolluru/ https://gauthamsk.me